<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cerberillo tech blog</title>
    <description>I’m a mobile develoepr that loves coding late in the night and test new stuff. Here you&#39;ll find some things that I&#39;ve been researching lately, currently working at PubNative, where there&#39;s a lot of nice people and freedom.
</description>
    <link>http://www.codingbehind.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.codingbehind.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2016 14:36:51 +0200</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2016 14:36:51 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.6</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Moving to Jekyll 3</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey there,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has been a couple of years pretty busy with my job at AppLift and PubNative, but the fact is that I would like to start writing my progression. Here is my new attempt and the starting point is moving the entire blog to Jekyll 3 which shown Itself very reliable and compatible with Github Pages :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy coding!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2016 00:12:46 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.codingbehind.com/2016/07/04/moving-to-jekyll-3.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.codingbehind.com/2016/07/04/moving-to-jekyll-3.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Java in OSX Yosemite</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve just updated to OSX Yosemite, which I found lean in the graphical part and very useful and way more powerful with the dynamic conexion between devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Picking up my phone in the laptop, open a couple of webs in the laptop and continue reading in the device because all of them are connected never was more easy and with better user experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other hand, I needed to do some Android java compilations and my ADT stopped working as soon as I installed OSX Yosemite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The solution is to install a fix released by apple that will enable Java6 in your new OSX.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For all of you that wanted to test th latest from Apple but still want to work with Android, &lt;a href=&quot;http://support.apple.com/kb/DL1572&quot;&gt;Here is the fix&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2014 16:50:23 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.codingbehind.com/2014/08/29/java-in-osx-yosemite.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.codingbehind.com/2014/08/29/java-in-osx-yosemite.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>New repository</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Finally I had some time to clean and extract some code from the dirt that I had in mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/cerberillo/Croissant&quot;&gt;You can find it here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a result of some bad experiences that I had with Objective-C, I’m talking about resource download. For some reason, Objective-C and Cocoa Isn’t enough prepared for downloading Async resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/library/mac/documentation/Cocoa/Conceptual/URLLoadingSystem/Tasks/UsingNSURLConnection.html&quot;&gt;I lie&lt;/a&gt;, Apple published a full async resource downloader, but the bad news is that It has to be re-worked in the exact same way every project you create needing that (Because Apple developers are lazy).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I decided to create a lean &amp;amp; simple resource downloader based in this functionality. The good point here is that I took the time to create a Downloader queue that let you download a configurable number of resources at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s based in 2 different types:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;DownloaderQueue: Controls the queue MAX downloads and automatically starts new downloads when needed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;DownloadItem: Controls a single download and notify the origin class.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now It has simple functionalities, download raw NSData and UIImages (for me, the 99% of the resources that are needed to be downloaded).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s easy to understand and easy to expand also with other types or queue control. I have in mind expanding it with pause/resume, so it will allow you to pause/resume long downloads (something that will be completely useless with iOS 8 and its background downloader).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the air I have a question: Shall I remove all the block oriented code? In my experience It doesn’t justify the effort maintaining such a buggy paradigm for not implementing callbacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy coding!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2014 01:09:02 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.codingbehind.com/objective-c/2014/08/19/new-repository.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.codingbehind.com/objective-c/2014/08/19/new-repository.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>objective-c</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Visiting Silicon Valley</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi There!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve recently visited Silicon Valley from San Francisco and just wanted to recap here how was it and give you some tips and tricks about how and what to visit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We decided that we were going to go to Silicon Valley almost 2 days before going, so we just rented a car and start searching what to see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our trip&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Stanford: One of the best universities of the world, it worth a visit and don’t underestimate it, a simple visit worth 2 hours minimum (just walk around the computer engineer buildings, the bookshop and all around the campus).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Computer History museum: We wanted to go here, but our Stanford visit delayed a couple of hours and we decided to continue our trip.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Googleplex: Goolge HQ’s where you can do nothing but taking a picture. We entered in the “visitor center” to be told that it’s a private place and nothing inside buildings can be visited, neither the café or the shop (that’s what I was searching for).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Apple: We went to Infinite loop street in cupertino and it looked also pretty much closed but with the exception that there’s an excelent place to have a lunch in front (BJ’s if I dont badly remember) and it has “The company store” like an apple store open to the public but with some company merchandising. It worth a visit to buy cheap stuff from the company and bring some special souverirs (Mugs, T-Shirts, Ballpens, etc).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Facebook: The most closed building of them all. Tinted glasses, security and a thumb’s up sign at the entrance of the “Hacker way” (Street where it is). It doesn’t deserve neither getting closer to it&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Believe it or not, this was a full day trip to Silicon valley and we didn’t had time for much more. I would recommend to visit Stanford, Apple and the Computer History museum that will have much more to see than Google or Facebook HQ’s.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2014 12:22:20 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.codingbehind.com/2014/07/29/visitng-silicon-valley.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.codingbehind.com/2014/07/29/visitng-silicon-valley.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Automatic work</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For certain reasons (unknowing, apathy, whatever) I’ve always hated the console, but at this point, I’m learning some scripting languages and I’m completely excited about the amount of personalised things that you can achieve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post is a result of 1 hour working to make 2 bash commands publish in tumblr for me&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Will I start loving this?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;F*ck XD&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 11:03:50 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.codingbehind.com/raw/2013/11/20/automatic-work.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.codingbehind.com/raw/2013/11/20/automatic-work.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>raw</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Microsoft spies us all</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Why, in the name of the Code, does M$ send me from time to time mails askinf me to connect again my Live account to Facebook, Twitter, etc…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are they entering into my account when I’m not looking at it?? Is that even fucking legal???&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fuck, I’m scared… XD2&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2013 18:05:43 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.codingbehind.com/raw/2013/11/19/Microsoft_spies_us_all.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.codingbehind.com/raw/2013/11/19/Microsoft_spies_us_all.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>raw</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Re-Start</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As you all can imagine, this is my new Blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve just restarted from scratch, bought a new domain (www.codingbehind.com) and prepared a cool tool to blog (octopress).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the last year, a lot of new things happened, I became dragon level programmer in Objective-C, Unity3D (which is pretty cool, since I worked a l0t in C# in the past) and started self-learning some server-side stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Damn! A lot of things changed since the last time I did a website. This blog is a Start, I’m hosting it in Heroku, generating it with Jekyll &amp;amp; started developing some services with Node.Js (I wanted to have some server new knowledge for testing).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, a lot of new things came over here, I hope this goes forward as far as I want to :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Coding!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2013 20:05:47 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.codingbehind.com/raw/2013/11/18/re-start.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.codingbehind.com/raw/2013/11/18/re-start.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>raw</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
